oh
[Music]
w
hello and welcome back to the ask abijit
Show episode what is it 176 welcome back
I hope you're all doing very well and
let us see who all is there on the live
chat as always let me greet all of you
as many of you as I can I can see Jay
tanay chag Rita harid borya hello
Anonymous gentlemen kaib G gin 1045 FES
hello aluminati Creek hello rajat Duan
as at Captain cool yummy krishanu Sharma
Captain Rogers ntin Ajay Kumar akula
milind as Manor hello
Arin Vladimir zeleski Imperial JP gaming
Sam sahu green ray tamat Tonga as Jin
threat Ripper abinav Jin I can see some
names being repeated okay bries sorab as
alok B suryya pan SAA fonga AR Singh AES
digpal ra gaming bab Tushar Thunder
Striker 303
arav NJ prna ronit Atara Chan rashadi
shauan gyroscope simply aib aay doc M
Dave Julie leoen boyfriend Raa ainash
Galaxy impact Sher poly discombobulation
hitan Dia s Arijit Paul Rohit prar
push henx Chetan rsr fter
fighter Deepak seventh day and and so
many more raki rajar reboot mankind Vish
mahanan Jay trupti trending 24 hours
trupti hello Jubal yes and so many so
many other people thank you so much for
being on this live stream live stream I
really appreciate this this live stream
as always is brought to you by my
geopolitics course geopolitics from
first principles many of you have asked
me to create a course so it is there the
link is in the description below the
link is ac. University check it out if
you wish to and with that let us get
into the questions so go ahead ask your
questions and I will try and take as
many of these questions as is possible
during this uh session so Rahul Sharma
says why is India's average IQ so low 84
some people say it's
82 first of all like Nasim Talib would
say IQ is a pseudo scientific Swindle
it's a joke they ask a number of
questions that see no question you can
ask is without a bias all questions have
some bias and if you are trained in
certain disciplines you may do better if
you don't have a that much training in
those disciplines you may not do that
well most IQ tests I would say 99.9% of
IQ tests are in the English language and
English is a foreign language for most
Indians so you take a random person give
them give him or her an IQ test in
English they may not understand the
questions that well there are so many
factors and so that is one thing I would
say that could contribute to these
so-called low IQ scores 84 82 whatever
you want to say you give people IQ tests
in their mother tongue you will see a
whole different set of scores that will
emerge out of it that's one and
secondly secondly there are other
factors as well let's say you have an
unbiased IQ test and still
hypothetically your your nation or or a
certain set of individuals a certain
data set scores low there could be other
factors behind it let's say you have a
nation that is suffering from
malnutrition when a person has suffered
from malnutrition as a child they're
going to have a decline they're going to
have lower than average intelligence and
all that I'm not saying India is a
country that suffers from Mal nutrition
today but historically India was starved
for two Centuries by the British and
some of that would persist some of that
would linger even in the 1960s '70s
maybe even the 80s you you had you know
Mal nutrition in India because of the
Socialist policies of the government so
some of that lingers there are lots of
factors you go to African nations and
you give them IQ tests in English and
they speak Zulu or Bantu or SW Swahili
or whatever they're going to do terribly
terribly in these IQ tests and there is
tremendous malnutrition in Africa and so
many other factors there are so many
factors that go into this and then
people give you the simplistic rankings
okay this nation has this IQ score that
is so stupid actually so you know if you
look at Indians outside of
India they typically do better than
everybody else so how does that Cor
relate with India's IQ scores and people
will argue that you send the India sends
the best of its people outside to the US
and all and that's why they do well well
that's not quite that much of an
argument overall Indians are I would say
some of the most intelligent people in
the world the average person may not be
that intelligent maybe but it's not the
average person that defines the
greatness of a
Nation the greatness of a nation is
defined by the 0.1 % the ones who true
the ones who truly contribute to the
nation and to the to the society and
take the society forward so all of you I
would say raise your standards try to be
among the
0.1% all right next
question next the
question rashtrawadi Shan says how to
become a polymath look you don't have to
be a polymath there is no need for a
person to be a polymath a polymath is a
person who is excellent in multiple
disciplines let's say you're excellent
in painting you excellent at playing
music you're excellent at mathematics
you're excellent excellent at history
and so on multiple disciplines
excellence in all in a number of
multiple disciplines that's called being
a polymath you don't have to be a
polymath if you most people aren't
equipped to be polymaths okay there's
nothing wrong with not being a polymath
there is nothing wrong with not having
expertise in 78 different subjects but
if you have that mental capacity and B
bandwidth if you are among those blessed
few then study spend time studying
reading acquiring knowledge acquiring
specific domain expertise in multiple
Fields it it even if you are that
intelligent it still takes a whole lot
of hard work to be a polyan so you to
dive deep into subjects deep deep deep
like significantly deep you spend hours
and hours countless hours of study you
know burning the midnight oil like they
say for years that's when you become
qualified it's not it's not easy it's
not something you can do in your spare
time
it has it's a full-time Endeavor so
there you have
it uh there is contact what manner of
contact are we speaking about have we
been contacted by an alien civilization
I don't know I'm just kidding I I'm sure
we have not all right so
um uh let's see what else do we have
um okay let's see this one t Pand says
universities in our country have
recently started mocking or making fun
of history epic ramayan what should be
done to teach these people a
lesson you know what this is freedom of
speech in India this is Indian
secularism we are a secular nation and
in India secularism means abusing and
mocking and disparaging the native
culture the native
civilization that's what secularism
means in
India this is something that will
eventually
change it's already the process of
change has already begun today there is
a significant push back when this
happens but these socalled University
professors and and academic staff they
are still mired in that Old Colonial
mindset they have gone through the
through the through the process through
the through the meat grinder of the
academic system which turns them into
zombies you know the academic system is
supposed to liberate you right
intellectually give the intellectual
tools to to truly intellectually
flourish it should it's supposed to give
you the ability to think critically and
to see the world in the way it really is
and to make a significant contribution
to the world and so on well the academic
system in India and abroad it it turns
it takes bright young children young
young kids with so much curiosity and
intelligence
and and all that and it it turns them
into
zombies and it not just turns them into
zombies and stultifies their ability to
think critically it not only kills their
creativity it not only creates their it
not just creates it not just kills their
curiosity and and
and and and exuberance and all that it
also brainwashes them into hating their
own
culture and these people eventually the
worst of the lot typically the ones who
who who comply the most with this they
rise to to become professors and they
rise to high positions in Academia and
then you will see things like this
happen so we need deep reforms in the
education system uh well not that not
that deep but okay I I won't say what I
just thought out aloud thought out but
yeah uh we need reforms you know gradual
proper reforms you know step by step
reforms nothing too drastic over a
period of let's say 10 20 years that's
that needs to happen
and more importantly it is for you all
to push back against this and you can't
go ahead and push back
physically but you can express
yourselves vocally and
vociferously on whatever platforms
you're on on social media on on whatever
else in in public and and push back
against this and the more this happens
the more uh the less likely it's going
to be that these people will keep on
doing this there's already a slow you
know tempering tempering down of this
Hindu phobia I'll tell you what India
India Barat is currently the world's
most Hindu phobic Nation okay even if
you go to certain uh let's say Middle
East countries Indians or Hindu Hinduism
gets gets better
treatment if you go to the US Hinduism
has people who are Hindus have more
rights than what they have in India
India is a hinduphobic apar state
because of the laws and the Constitution
and and the policies of the of the
various governments you know I mean
state level Etc governments things are
changing things will change it will take
time we have we have come out of several
centuries of foreign occupation and our
you know institutions our laws all of
that are deeply colonized even now and
our academic academic Personnel are
deeply deeply mentally colonized they're
the worst possible people to teach our
kids anything and yet they're in charge
so uh I'm not going to talk about giving
you know teaching these people a lesson
what these people are merely symptoms of
a deeper disease of a deeper malay we
have to address the root cause not teach
these people a lesson you have to
address the root cause by by changing
the system by reforming the system by
reforming India's institutions by
reforming the laws the Constitution all
of that it's going to take a deep rooted
change it's going to take a long time
but it'll happen and what we all can do
is push back against this nonsense call
them out sha name and shame them and uh
if possible take legal action because
I'm sure that even within India's
horrific system U I'm pretty sure that
abusing religions even the native
religions uh is is probably illegal okay
you can take a look at the laws and if
possible take legal action if this
happens but yes there needs to be push
back significant push back against this
I'm not talking talking about teaching
people lessons or or you know resorting
to any form of violence but take proper
action legally acceptable action and
yeah that's what needs to happen more
and more and we're going to see a push
back against this all
right uh let us see what else we have
uh let's
see chag says why is Ukraine talking so
much to India and what's the whole
geopolitical agenda behind the foreign
Minister's visit to New Delhi look the
West would like India to tow its line
the West is in US EU NATO all that
essentially the West means the us all
these so-called Western nations are
proxies of the US the US is the great
Empire the sole superpower and the US
would like India to to its line or kind
of come to towards its its side when it
comes to the Ukraine war when it comes
to sanctions against Russia when it
comes to India stands on Ukraine and
Russia and the whole situation all that
they would like India to be on their
side and they will try various PL and
various uh and and various kinds of
actions from various angles to try and
nudge India towards coming in on on in
their Camp right so uh and as we know
Ukraine is not a free country it's a
it's a proxy of the US uh the current
conflict in Ukraine is a proxy war
between Russia and the US and the two
proxies are NATO and Ukraine and NATO is
a proxy of the US and Ukraine is also a
proxy of the US Ukraine is a porn on the
big geopolitical chessboard the
Americans have put that pawn forward and
that pawn is being obliterated by Russia
Russia has been left with no choice
Ukraine is going to eventually seize to
exist the in the shape and form that it
is today about a quarter of the nation
of Ukraine has already been eaten up by
Russia the donbas region Russian
majority region Russian speaking region
anyway eventually the nation of Ukraine
is going to be partitioned most likely
along the dier river and that's
eventually most likely going to be uh
its fate so uh if the Ukrainian foreign
minister comes to India he's essentially
an ambassador of the West and he has
been uh essentially told to visit India
and try and extract some kind of
concession or something from India so
overall it doesn't make uh any big
difference India is not going to change
its uh geopolitical priorities its
geopolitical stand just because somebody
came and spoke to us our national
interest comes first as does the
national interest of every country every
nation has to prioritize their National
interest in the case of the EU nations
in the case of the NATO Nations they are
forced to prioritize a different
nation's interest over
theirs that is why those nations are not
genuinely Sovereign
Nations understand the meaning of
sovereignty
India is a genuinely Sovereign Nation
there are maybe four nations in the
world that are genuinely Sovereign one
is the US the superpow the global Empire
the second is Russia fully Sovereign no
one can tell Russia what to do third is
China fourth is India the four Sovereign
Nations and there are other nations that
you would imagine are very powerful that
are not truly Sovereign you think
Germany is a Sovereign Nation haha you
think France is Sovereign France is more
Sovereign than than Germany much more
Sovereign but not fully Sovereign you
think Japan is Sovereign Japan is a
nation under permanent military
occupation foreign occupation and so on
so when it comes to Ukraine the foreign
minister coming to India and talking it
doesn't really make much of a difference
for us we will entertain the person
we'll go and talk to the person and give
give that person a proper welcome as is
befitting the status of a foreign
minister of a country but nothing beyond
that it makes no big difference all
right enough about that let's take a
different question tun t
welcome thank you so much for becoming a
member appreciate it and I hope that you
gain something of value here as I'm sure
will you will and thank you once
again okay as says I'm a second
generation Indian immigrant in the UK
studying at Imperial in nuclear
engineering I'm interested in
researching in torium based small
modular reactors do I have a chance in
India
well I'm assuming you are a UK citizen
well when it comes to research in
nuclear technology research on nuclear
technology in India I'm not sure foreign
Nationals would be uh given an entry
into that first of all in case you're
not a foreign national uh but you are
living in the UK there may be
scrutiny if you want to come to India
and do research in thorium based
reactors uh then I'm sure there will be
some extra scrutiny on on your
background from the Indian well the
government of India let's just say and
let's say you pass the scrutiny you're
you're in then I'm not
sure whether there is research at the
University or academic level when it
comes to thorium based uh reactors I'm
not sure there is the research that is
indeed happening would happen at the
level of the Baba Atomic Research Center
and various other uh you know institutes
or or or institutions where you have
research being conducted because this is
kind of sensitive technology nucle
nuclear technology is something that
very few nations in the world have and
there is currently whether you realize
or not I'm sure you do my friend there
is a race for uh Supremacy in thorium
technology and India is one of the
Nations that's at the Forefront of
thorium uh research thorium reactor
research so it is pretty sensitive this
this particular Feld this particular
domain there's going to be a small
number of people who going to be working
on this they're going to have a certain
level of security clearance pretty high
level of security clearance and so on so
I'm not sure that if you are a foreign
National or a foreign res resident
there's a lot of scope for you to do
research on thorium based Technologies
reactors in India even India itself has
I would say I don't know how many
students get a degree um master's degree
in nuclear physics every year I'm must
I'm sure that's tens of thousands and
how many of them get to work on this
maybe a handful maybe every year 10 or
20 of those so yeah there's tremendous
competition and there's uh so I think I
think it's pretty difficult just being
completely transparent and honest with
you it's pretty difficult to do this in
India I know I understand where you come
where you're coming from you are of
Indian origin you may want to give back
to to your well Homeland but I I would
say the chances are slim but there's no
harm if you're really good at what you
do you may stand a chance so I would say
that be be realistic that the chances
may be less but if you're really good at
what you do then it's possible it's
possible that if you are like one of the
brilliant students or researchers you
may get a chance perhaps there you have
it okay next what do we have
next uh
um let us see what
else sidart sing rajo says can BCC what
can BCCI do to make cricket a global
sport like football in the last World
Cup we only had 10 teams there should
should there be more teams in the World
Cup just like FIFA World Cup look it's a
great great question actually the FIFA
World Cup has I mean every single nation
essentially plays
football uh you go to a small island
let's say in the South Pacific like
Tonga like the Solomon Islands or
whatever you you'll find kids playing
football there you won't find kids
playing Cricket there Cricket is that
weird
sport It's actually an Indian sport that
the British reinvented so if you go back
to the days of the Mahabharat okay and
you read about the Leela of Sri Krishna
when he was a kid when the Great Shri
Krishna was a kid he used to play on the
banks of the yamuna and at one point in
time he hits his ball hits a ball with
is bat and what happens the ball goes
and falls into the river and then he has
to go and fight a gigantic snake to get
the ball back what game was he playing
he was playing a game of bat and ball so
it's actually an Indian sport that the
British somehow reinvented anyhow now
today the sport of cricket is played
only where the British colonized uh
whatever countries colonized for a
certain amount of time so India and
Pakistan the entire Indian subcontinent
everybody took to it naturally because
it is kind of originally an Indian game
okay
but apart from that it's only a few
countries where the where people even
know that this game exists so it's hard
to to you know make uh to expand the
World Cup of course I think 12 teams is
way too less why could you have teams
like Zimbabwe or or Kenya that have
played in the past why can't you have
them play in the World Cup why don't you
also open doors for Nations like Hong
Kong for instance or or whoever else
Namibia I mean let's have some diversity
I don't know why it has to be just 10
teams I totally agree with the sentiment
there should be at least 12 or 14 teams
expand the field a little bit have the
Netherlands come in there are plenty of
countries that play reasonably good
Cricket Ireland Scotland uh and so on so
I agree I'm not sure why it's it's such
a such a narrow narrow field that they
that they've made the last time so I
don't know what is the reason why they
did that I hope in the next World Cup
it's it's more expanded a slightly wider
field to give us a little more iety and
a little more more diversity but I don't
know what what what is behind this maybe
it's about money maybe that if Kenya
plays uh Namibia that nobody will watch
I don't know what it is but ideally we
should have more so I agree with
you pinky Devi says Raja haris Singh had
sent two or three times the instrument
of accession of Jammu and Kashmir to Mr
Neu Shri Neu G the great magnificent Mr
Neu G but Shri Neu G rejected it
yes sometimes it is there that he wanted
a separate state was it pro India or not
I'm assuming you are asking me about Shu
G so Shri so the Maharaja of Jammu and
Kashmir Shri haris Singh G Maharaj haris
Singh G had sent the signed letter of
letter of accession the instrument of
accession to the government of India New
Delhi which is Mr Neu three times on
three occasions it was the exact same
instrument of accession that every other
princely states signed and Mr Neu kept
on rejecting it eventually it was
accepted by Mr Mount bat not Mr Neu and
that was after the pakistanis had
already sent their troops into Jammu and
Kashmir and Shri nagar was kind of under
threat already you know so I don't know
what Mr Neu wanted maybe he wanted the
whole state of Jammu and Kashmir to go
to Pakistan I'm not sure what he wanted
but his actions not make any sense
considering the fact that the Indian
prime minister is supposed to prioritize
India's national interest not the
national interest of other nations so Mr
Neu is is One of a Kind unique person
he's most oldtime people oldtimers they
worship Mr Naru the the the father of
what they what do they call it
scientific temper oh good God was he a
scientist no no he was the father of
scientific temper what does scientific
temper mean I I still don't know what it
means but yes it was a very logical
rational person a man of scientific
temper he loved speaking English nobody
spoke English as well is him not even
the great Mr T he used to smoke I don't
know what sort of cigars he used to have
a an a plane Air India plane go to the
West every every other day to get in
more cigars and have his you know dress
properly pressed and all so I don't know
he was he was truly a magnificently
great man I just probably he was too
great for ordinary people like us to
understand so I don't know really I
don't know I I seem simply uh I met a
loss when it comes to the actions of the
great Fu
G
okay tarun TSC says hello G there is
this man with a channel called whatever
he has reacted to me please answer back
to him he's getting very annoyed and
biased look I don't know who this is
look you know the other day I was
walking on the street and there were
some monkeys howling at
me should I have howled back at them you
go walk on the street there'll be a
dogie a dog who's going to bark at you
for whatever reason you're going to bark
back at him or her
you don't react to just about
anybody no point if someone's annoying
and biased you ignore them okay so I am
not interested in uh having this back
and forth nonsense this
apologies to children who may be
watching but I'm not into that I'm I I
won't be doing that thank you
sorry
okay um um um
um nameless says sir if anybody has to
start studying geopolitics where should
he begin with from please guide me begin
with my geopolitics course geopolitics
from first principles the link is ac.
University and if you do not wish to
purchase a course because it cost money
then start studying history spend a lot
of time studying world history not
history of your local you know
municipality just just kidding but study
world history spend a lot of time
ideally 5 to 10 years devouring world
history ancient history more modern
history history from Europe history from
Egypt history from China Japan
Mesopotamia India as well despite it
being so horrifically uh depressing at
times at least the past Thousand Years
study world history study the brutality
study the empires the rise and fall of
Empires do that over and over again and
the more you do it the more it will
become par to you that history repeats
itself in Cycles in cycles and cycles
and those and it is because the human
psychology has always been the same
human psychology is the same whether it
is 10,000 years ago or today and you
will find that those Cycles are still in
play at play today and that's how you
will start understanding geopolitics and
the motivations behind various
geopolitical actions so that's how you
do it or you can take a shortcut and
study my course which gives you
principles straightforward principles
and so on all right that should be that
should be yeah that's answer
H
okay now what
else
um kaib says when is Dr ry's paper
coming out I'm assuming you're talking
about Dr NJ R the
geneticist at the Bal sahani Institute
of molecular bi genetics or whatever it
is a great guy doing tremendous research
and I'm not sure what the paper is
coming in uh it's a paper about uh
India's genetic makeup uh it's
essentially about the r1a star Hao
group uh I believe they have collected
the data but I'm not sure when the paper
will come in so how about I give him a
call today tomorrow whenever May
tomorrow it's a little late today and
and let let me find out yeah I'll try
and find out what exactly what is the
exact situation right now what's the
status uh any any idea when it's going
to published so I personally don't know
right now but I'll try and find
out okay Thunder Striker 303 I got a
question for you what impact did the
Industrial Revolution have on global
economics and societies so the
Industrial Revolution was something that
brought in
automation machine automation into lots
of things so there was more
standardization of goods goods and
products and there was a very rapid Pace
at which goods and products could be
churn out compared to before automation
happened so you first had the steam
Revolution uh the British uh the English
man James wat was the inventor of the
steam engine which uh would eventually
go on to drive those you know Railways
trains but it also was something that
was used in various industrial
applications it had lots of industrial
applications
so you had Goods being mass produced as
a consequence of the Industrial
Revolution you had more standardization
of goods and all that so a lot so one of
the things it did was that industries
were concentrated became concentrated in
specific regions in specific areas
typically in metropolitan areas so
historically so this happened this
Industrial Revolution came out of
England essentially it spread across
Europe eventually so before the
Industrial Revolution the elite the
elite of English
society were the land owners okay the
nobility the aristocracy they were they
used to own large tracts of land and
they were wealthy because that land was
agricultural land they would have
peasants work on that and they would
give those peasant a little bit of money
and a small place to stay in but they
would you know earn the the the in
massive income from the agricultural
produce that comes out of that land so
before the Industrial Revolution the
main source of Revenue money wealth was
land and agricultural produce and the
big landowning
families were the elite of society and
they were given these
lands as a reward for services rendered
to the queen or the king to the crown
essentially so all land belonged to the
crown and these land owners these Lords
Etc they were given lands to administer
and they would make money off it and
obviously they would pay a big big tax
to the crow that's how it was after the
Industrial
Revolution the the elite of society
changed now the big money would come in
from mass produced
Goods so the industrialists became the
new Elite and the land owners uh they
they slowly faded Into Obscurity big
owning big tracts of land became
eventually a liability because those
peasants who are working toiling away on
your Fields they now migrated to the
cities to work in the
big uh what do you call them
factories so that's what happened so the
whole you know makeup of society changed
and then you had this this you
know the rise of Corporations the rise
of quarter upon quarter profits the
quarterly statements and all that so
Society has changed very much and then
you had you know people working in
shifts 8 Hour 8 Hour 8 hour shifts 24
hours you could have factors running and
so on so it tremendously transformed
society and eventually it transformed
the whole world so that's in a very
brief answer the gist of what happened
and you could you know have a a one
semester course on the effects that this
had on the
world okay abishek Sam says what
actually happened on the nandi mountain
did the American lose a nuclear spy
device there the sanctuary is still out
of bounds for regular
hikers
so this is during the time of the
Chinese invasion of Tibet in in the
aftermath so the Chinese invasion of
Tibet happened in the
1950s The Invasion and annexation which
was helped by Mr Neu giving China the
Chinese soldiers rice to so that they
would not starve Mr nrow was magnificent
then you had the 1962 war and so on and
then there was some to some extent a
certain amount of cooperation between
India and the US and the Americans
wanted to spy on the Chinese activities
in Tibet in Chinese occupied Tibet so
they wanted to place some kind of
devices I'm not sure whether it was a
telescope or whether it was some kind of
other device but it was an an electronic
device that needed power and they want
and this had to be placed on in the
Himalayas which which is like the the
temperatures are frighteningly bad there
like in winter it's like -30 - 35 in lak
and so on so the temperatur is really
really drop and any instrumentation that
you keep there will totally Freeze and
stop functioning in that sort of that
sort of temperature so you need a
heating device it needs to be heated and
kept warm otherwise it will it will not
work so one of the uh ways to do it is
to use a small amount of
plutonium okay so a small amount of
plutonium and a kind of spy device I'm
not I don't remember what kind of spy
device it was but it was a kind of
device uh probably to keep track of
Chinese activities so you had a
plutonium device and that was kept up on
top of a mountain and then the next
spring when you go back there the device
is missing and this kind of this region
this terrain is prone to avalanches and
earthquakes as well the Himalayas are
are still Rising this massive tectonic
activity happening there you had a few
years ago a massive earthquake in Nepal
and you have regular quakes you know low
intensity earthquakes that happen all
the time in the Himalayas so let's say
uh small Tremor which is like RoR like 3
3.54 on the RoR scale that would happen
every week I would say and you also have
Avalanches which is this massive you
know this massive amount of amounts of
snow that fall down a mountain when
something whatever there's a big noise
or for whatever reason when the snow
becomes unstable in the slopes so it's
quite likely that maybe there's there
was a you know reasonably minor
earthquake that dislodged the apparatus
from the instrument from where it was
kept or maybe there was an avalanch that
swept it away or something or maybe
there was some other thing that
happened okay so maybe that device is
still somewhere out there and it's still
got that plutonium which is heating it
and plutonium is I would I must tell you
it's an extremely toxic element first of
all it doesn't occur naturally plutonium
plutonium is something that
you create in nuclear reactors as part
of a nuclear reaction and you typically
have a breeder reactor that that does
that okay I not go into the physics of
it but it's an artificially created
element it doesn't occur naturally on
Earth and it is extremely toxic even in
very minute quantities it is toxic one
of the worst case scenarios is somebody
well I should not say it but if you
contaminate water with plutonium it's
going to cause a tremendous amount of
deaths so PL name is very dangerous very
toxic you typically keep it very well
sealed but if it that device is indeed
lost then it makes sense that that
region would be out of bounds for
regular hikers and some people have
speculated that maybe the Indian
government went and took this device so
that it could examine it and figure out
how it works and maybe take the
plutonium or something like that all
theories there is no real uh no real
answer to what really happened we don't
know but yeah that is the deal
world of facts says break down the
current situation of Bangladesh Army
versus cookie National Army after
looting a bank by the cookie National
Army in Bangladesh okay I was not aware
of the Looting of a bank by the cookies
in Bangladesh but well that's something
they typically would do so this cookie
thing okay where's the
map where is the map we need to see the
map because we talking about something
that is geographically related so here
is the map let's let's zoom in
okay we're talking about the far East of
India we're talking about
Bangladesh so these cookie people they
are they
historically were native to the region
of yan in present day China okay then
they a few centuries ago they migrated
into what is currently Burma these
cookies they don't speak the Burmese
language they don't practice the Burmese
culture they are not even Burmese and
now they're fighting a war against Burma
they're fighting a war against
Bangladesh and they fighting a war
against India they fighting a war
against three nations to create a nation
in Christ a nation of Christ so the
Bangladesh Army is fighting the
cookies and the burmes Army is fighting
the cookies and in India we give cookies
other cards so that is the deal and now
now I think it's very clear that the
cookies are kind of a big threat to the
to the
nation and they aren't Indian okay they
may have acquired other cards or
whatever they may have have they may be
occupying land in India but they aren't
Indians and just because somebody is
born in in India they don't get Indian
citizenship and so on so I'll not go
into this I've spoken about this at
length many times uh but yes the cookies
are fighting Bangladesh and the
Bangladesh Army will obviously take
action against them uh so that's what I
can say in brief I was not aware of the
fact they've looted some bank I don't
keep track of what's happening on a
day-to-day basis because it's kind of
tedious but I can tell you that this
situation this entire situation that you
we seeing in the Far East of India in
the Manipur mizoram region it's not some
local Rebellion or or local infiltration
by some ragtag bunch of bunch of savage
foreigners it's geopolitical matter and
there are bigger outside forces at play
in this by bigger outside forces I'm I'm
talking about there are two or three
nations that are more powerful and
larger than India in the world it's a
couple of those that are involved in
this okay chag says despite the being a
superpower why couldn't they stop the
rise of China they far from stopping the
rise of China the Americans have aided
and ab beted the rise of China they have
midwifed the birth of China as you know
a potential great power not a superpower
but a potential great power so yeah
that's what the Americans have done the
Chinese were in danger of being nuked by
the Soviet Union in 1969 after the
Chinese fought the the Soviets in the
Far East of Russia of the USSR along the
usuri river would you like to see where
it is let me bring it on the screen
where's the map here is the map so the
Far East of Russia is this and then you
have the sakin
peninsula then you have Kamchatka the
island yes and then you have this region
so somewhere around
here is the usuri
river where is this River let me find
this is the Amur River but somewhere
here is the URI river that kind
of see the usuri river this is the usuri
river and this kind of defines the
border of Russia and China today now
there's an island along this river which
I will I be able to locate it it'll be
somewhere around
here okay let's see where is this
island um okay it's somewhere around
here okay it may take some time for me
to located I will spare you the teds
search procedure it's somewhere around
here there was a there were massive
clashes between the USR and China along
the lines of the India China clashes
along the disputed India Tibet border
the undemarcated border and the Soviets
had decided to Nuke China the Americans
came to know about this and they said if
you guys nuke China we're going to Nuke
you so they threatened nuclear war and
that's how the Soviets kind of pulled
back and then the Americans had this de
ta with China during the uh era during
the presidency of Richard
Nixon when HRI kinger was the Secretary
of State and that's how China slowly
started opening up to the US and China
became the manufacturing Hub they would
manufacture whatever the Americans
needed at much lower rates than what the
Americans could manufacture because of
because their workers had to be paid
more and so on and as a result of this
over a few decades there was a
tremendous amount of technological
transfer and all that and the Chinese
became this massive manufacturing power
and that's how they became an economic
power otherwise they were nowhere they
were so the Americans aided and abetted
the rise of China it it's only after the
the the ascent of Xi Jinping to the
presidency of China that China became
this you know they started acting up and
behaving like a threat to the
US so yeah the Americans actually did
that and they want to ensure that they
don't repeat that mistake with
India okay okay what
next Arjun Agarwal says do you think the
current sci-fi science fiction is
becoming mostly dystopian absolutely
absolutely I read a lot I have read a
lot I have been reading science fiction
especially uh since I was a kid since I
was what seven eight years old I've read
a lot of Science Fiction I've read a lot
of Science Fiction from the 1940s 50 60s
okay and if you read old science fiction
very quaint we science fiction if you
see that it's a very
utopian uh utopian kind of literature
you know uh in which mankind goes out to
The Stars humankind goes out to The
Stars meets aliens and sometimes there
is war sometimes there is cooperation
whatever but it's it's overall very
optimistic and if you look at today's
Science Fiction it's all about dystopia
it's about a nuclear Wasteland it's
about Humanity has destroyed the Earth
and then something happens it's all p
istic negative
dystopia and it tells you the direction
that Western Society has taken because
this is all science fiction that's being
written out of the West is there anybody
in India that write science fiction no
no Indians don't write science fiction
what a
joke they'll write God knows what but
they won't write science fiction because
okay I'll not go there so most of this
science fiction is it's it comes out of
the West okay uh and it ref reflects the
the mindset of today's society so the
science fiction that was written in the
1960s 1950s that reflected the worldview
that the West had at that time it was a
very positive optimistic worldview today
it's very negative so yes I agree with
you Arjun that today's science fiction
has become is becoming increasingly
dystopian and negative and pessimistic
and that just represents the current
mindset of the society in the west which
is not positive at all uh if you talk
about the US they they are no longer a
nation that believes in exceptionalism
they are a nation that believes in
mediocrity the US believes in mediocrity
look see the kind of cultural
manifestation that's coming out of the
West go to we don't have Tik Tok in
India thankfully we banned that go to
Instagram res or whatever and see the
kind of culture they are showing
today it it is it's
cringeworthy and these standards have
dropped
the quality of life has dropped go to
New York and see the quality of life
there there are people barbecuing Rats
on the on the streets and all so yeah as
the nation as the US becomes more and
more dystopian science fiction is also
becoming more and more dystopian it's
simply a reflection of the state of
society in the
west costum says your opinion on the
Diego Garcia Island issue I have made a
whole video about this just a week or so
ago check the video out I have given my
opinion in that
okay Anish says have you watched the
three body problem I've seen one episode
I hardly get time to watch TV or watch
anything on TV but I have seen the first
episode a couple of weeks back I thought
the first episode was fine I haven't
seen the rest of it but I have read the
books so I think I've not read all the
books I think I've read the first book
and some part of the second book and
then I ran out of time the first book
was great the second book probably I'm
sure it's great as well so the books are
great it's by a Chinese author called
chickin Liu or something like that great
books but uh I'm not sure how good the
series is the the the Netflix series is
the first episode was not bad I don't
mind watching the second one but after
that I don't know so
yeah sahil sahu says why was Burma
separated from India and why didn't it
join India after Independence Burma was
okay map where's the map
here is the map I hope my dear friends
you know where Burma is Myanmar it's now
called Myanmar it's this nation to the
east of
India and it adjoins the Indian states
of missor Manipur nagaland and arunachal
Pradesh so this nation was part of the
British Raj it was part of British India
okay and culturally it is very Indian
Myanmar even Thailand is culturally very
very Indian well the whole of Southeast
Asia is culturally very Indian all the
way to Japan actually whether people
realize it or not so Burma
Myanmar it was part of British India and
in 1935 okay mark my
words in
1935 the people of Myanmar the people of
Burma voted to not dissociate from India
they wanted to remain part of India in
and they actually voted to remain part
of India and despite that vote the
British separated Burma from
India and then once such things
happen history takes its own
course I mean Jun also was hoping
apparently it is said that this was just
a temporary matter the partition of
India and Pakistan eventually we'll all
come back together once you take a
certain step you know history the the
the chains the the wheels of History
will take you in a whole different
direction so Burma was partitioned
forcibly from India by the British 1935
Burma had voted to stay part to remain
part of India and the godamn British
partian Burma should not have been
partitioned the burmes did not want to
separate from India the British did this
the British have done so much harm to
the world if you if there is a disaster
that's going on in the Far East of India
in Manipur and in Burma as well it is
entirely a consequence of what the
British did to this region the root
cause of the Civil War in Northern Burma
and the root cause of the cookie
infiltration of into Manipur is Britain
is the British Invasion and occupation
of this region every bad thing once you
go to the root of it you will find the
Brit British the root of it so yeah
there you have it there you have
it okay
ah okay I'll I'll skip the
name what
lessons Austin Powers is
it what lessons from rulers in the past
can India learn today what traits are
necessary for future Prime Ministers and
military leaders to adopt first of all
one lesson that we should learn from the
past our past history is that India
should not be ruled by prime ministers
go back to the times when India was at
the peak of its game go back to the
times in India's history the past 3,000
years let's say when India
was politically unified and India was
tremendously prosperous and tremendously
successful militarily did we have a
prime minister ruling the country no we
had an emperor ruling the country and
that Emperor was typically a military
military
leader that's not rule that's lesson
number one so India was India a
democratic country when India was at its
peak multiple times in the past go back
to the time of chhatrapati shivaji
Maharaj in the in the marata Empire go
back to the time of the Chulas when
India conquered the whole of Southeast
Asia go back to the time of lad mapa
when India conquered Central Asia go
back to the time of the Gupta Empire
when India conquered bik and and what is
today's Afghanistan Tajikistan tanan
region go back to the time of keska the
the kushan when India conquered Tibet
and sing Jang and had territories that
touched the shores of the Caspian SE in
the Aral SE go back to the morian Empire
when India conquered reconquered freed
gandha from the from the Greeks and so
on go back to these times when India was
great did we have democracy did we have
Prime Ministers did we have Chief
ministers no we had EMP we had
Emperors lots of very straightforward
lessons India can learn from
history okay what traits are necessary
for Future Leaders forget about prime
ministers leaders National interest
comes first be ruthless with enemies and
uh crush your enemies see them driven
before you and so on if you know what I
mean
okay abijit why don't you write sci-fi I
I've never written fiction and secondly
firstly I've never written fiction
secondly I have no time these days I
have no time but yeah maybe I will write
sci-fi one day maybe who knows I may be
good at it I never knew that I was good
at talking I never knew that I was good
at being online on a live stream and
actually people would listen to me I had
no idea so you got to try something
before you know it works or not so who
knows if I write
sci-fi I may be good or maybe I'll be
terrible who knows but unless I try it I
won't know but there are other things I
would like to do before I try my hand at
sci-fi I'd like to go back to actual
science for a change so we'll see about
that but yeah thank you for the
suggestion and I appreciate
that
okay okay sh Jin pinky
amama Shri
Jinping uh okay I saw many Western
History Channels saying that the British
had not colonized India then the Dutch
or the French or the Portuguese would
have India was it that easy sir I don't
think it was that easy the British were
the the British were the most Insidious
of the
lot uh what the British succeeded in
doing was that they succeeded in
defeating the marata Empire that had
already liberated most of India from
turkic
occupation so the marata Empire
stretched from all the way in the South
to all the way up to the some parts of
Afghanistan they had genuinely liberated
India from tur occupation and the
British destroyed that they destroyed
hind swaja okay so they were good at
that they did this everywhere I don't
think the Dutch or the French or the
Portuguese were that good that defeating
U entrenched Empires or civilization
it's not that easy and the British were
really good at that and their succeeding
their successor successor State the
Americans are also very good at that so
uh it wasn't that easy I don't think if
the British had let's say The British
failed at defeating the marata
Empire and let's say the marata empire
did not
self-destruct and and kick the British
out then I don't think the Dutch of the
French of the Portuguese would have
succeeded the tussle was between the
marata Empire and the British and
because of infighting the marata Empire
became weak there were assassinations
and so on among themselves read
history and because of infighting the
British were able to take advantage
let's say there was no infighting in the
marata Empire let's say it remained
strong and let's say it defeated the
British then it would have been so
strong that nobody else could have been
able to defeat them so these so-called
History Channels they are giving you a
very simplistic
analysis and very
rather fanciful analysis I don't think I
would not agree with with this uh uh
with what they are
saying
okay okay J P says should I make my
marriage into a business contract
between my future wife and I because I
think marriage is not love or sentiments
but business transactions in a b in a
marriage partnership look the Western
worldview the Christian worldview is
that marriage is a social contract okay
and it's typically binding as long as
the the two parties are married but it
can dissolve inve in divorce and
typically in the west marriage lasts
between I don't know 6 months to two
years to maybe 5 years if you're lucky 7
10 years but eventually people get
divorced there are like multiple
marriages or then some people choose not
to marry and so on so I'm not sure J
where you live whether you're Indian or
some some from somewhere else but it
depends on the context of the society
that you live in are people look there
are so societies where people are
extremely promiscuous where extramarital
Affairs and adultery and infidelity is
normal uh Nations like okay I'll not
take names because what's the point uh
or if and there are some societies where
you have you know you still have
Fidelity where most partners are remain
loyal to each other there are there is
much lower incidence of of these of
infidelity of cheating and all that so
it depends it depends in India also
these days I I hear I'm not seen but I
hear that there is this
uh you know there's this rise especially
in metropolitan areas in urban areas of
of people having multiple sexual
partners and and whatnot if that becomes
the norm then obviously it makes sense
for you to perhaps look at marriage from
a realistic pragmatic perspective a
geopolitical perspective and not from
emotional perspective but you know
traditionally in India marriage has been
something that you have for life and uh
yeah but it depends on the context it
entire depends on the context and the
environment that you are in if you're in
that sort of culture or Society or
country where it is well you know people
get get married and get divorced quickly
and then the whoever the person you
marry will ask for half of your money
and you legally have to you are legally
obligated to pay that then it makes
sense to have a prubal um you know
agreement or something like that so it
depends on the context but you got to be
careful I would say today's world world
the world has always complicated but you
got to be
careful
okay Swami Jen says why were Indians be
chested in the past even in Winter look
I'm I'm sure that if you if you were
living in gandhar in Winter you would
not be be chested unless you
were unless you were a sadu who wanted
to do tapasia so even today theal as you
will see
sados in in in ladak and all who will be
wearing just a bit of cloth on their on
their below the waist and they can take
the temperature freezing temperes I
don't know how that is the incredible
resilience of the human mind more than
the body but a standard person a regular
person living in gandar in October in
December in February I promise you they
will not be be chested okay but if a
person were living in let's say
tanur or let's say
um so somewhere in the south then even
in Winter where when the weather is mild
you can afford to be be bare chested so
I don't think Indians were always bare
chested okay I don't think it was always
the case depends on the climate depends
on where you're living what latitude
you're living in if you're living below
the Tropic of Cancer even in winter it's
going to be reasonably Pleasant it won't
be very very cold so you may enjoy the
weather and you can you may be able to
remain you know topless be chested
but if you were in so that's what I mean
so there is no evidence that our
ancestors were always be chested no
matter the temperature doesn't make
sense right but yeah typically when you
see Indian statues and carvings in
temples uh from before The turkic
Invasion era you typically see people
who are be chested male or female
because at least in in in summer and in
Spring and and all it was the
temperature was really reasonably hot
and it made sense not to wear that much
clothing so yeah it's it's nuanced his
history is not that black and white and
simplistic it's nuanced you will see for
example in in carvings from the Gandhara
region present day pakist know
Afghanistan you will see in some cases
people wearing Shaws and all that as
well but you will also see be chest
people so it will depend on the on the
season all right
um chak the football says will Indian
football ever rise the moment you pour
money into a sport that sport Rises
Indian do you I mean I'm not sure if you
remember I've been watching Cricket for
for a long time
uh I saw India play Pakistan live in the
1992 World Cup when I was a kid and
that's the first time India beat
Pakistan in the world cup so I've seen
the whole progress of of Indian cricket
Indian cricketers used to be
unfit and
weak bad
fielders bad Runners until the IPL
happened the IPL brought in tremendous
amounts of money and when you are being
paid that much you better be
professional and then you had all these
coaches and trainers and medical uh
sports sports medicine personal coming
in and today you have the best athletes
in cricket tremendous fielders
tremendous Runners even domestic
cricketers the the fitness standards
have become world
class and the quality of the game has
become world class even among domestic
cricket players in
India so Money Changes Everything the
moment you have the sort of money that's
poured into football everything's going
to
change so that's all that's all it takes
today you have somewhat Indian Football
League or something uh not or what it's
called and it happens a couple of times
uh a year a couple of months a year or
something but it's not at the same level
the moment you have proper money going
into a football league and know in a
football league that lasts six to eight
months with like three or four months
off season that's when things
change so it's all about money it's all
about money nothing else football will
rise the moment people somebody
invests money into
it
okay okay laui miaar says can you retold
can you retell the Battle of Vienna 1683
a turning point for Europe between the
European Empire and the Ottoman Empire
at their Peak and how is the date linked
with the date of 911
attack1 okay I'm not sure about the link
with the 911 attack in 2001 but the
Battle of Vietnam was
when what's his name suan the
Magnificent was
it born on November 6 whatever year I
know November 6 but I don't remember
which year suan the Magnificent he is
the guy who is considered to be the
greatest of the Ottoman uh Kings Sultans
and uh he was called the canoni the
lawgiver he called himself the shadow of
God on
Earth and he made one great bid
for for Continental domination when he
hammered at the gates of Vienna and
seized the Christian World by its
throat and the he sieged he besieged
Vienna for several
months but he could not break through
and he had to eventually Retreat so that
was the turning point from that day
onwards the Ottoman Empire you could
say that that was the the the point at
which it was stopped and then repelled
and the repulsion did not happen over
night it took decades it took centuries
but you could say perhaps that that's
the Turning Point that's where the slow
decline eventually
begins uh so that's the Battle of
Vietnam 1683 I don't remember which year
it is I'm assuming that what you saying
is Right 1683 so yeah that was it uh and
I am not sure if there is any connection
with 9/11 20
2001 I'm not sure I was not aware of
this so I cannot answer that part of
your question I don't know of any
connection but that's the Battle of
Vietnam and the Turks are beat were
beaten back at that
okay okay doc M says talk about Iran
retaliation possibilities and Israel's
response further well now you asking me
to talk about all kinds of potential
scenarios okay let's take a look at the
map because we need the map for for this
so we know that Israel has attacked just
a few days ago the Iranian Consulate in
Damascus so Israel is this nation on the
Eastern shores of the Mediterranean Sea
and Damascus is over here the capital of
Syria would you like to see the place
where this attack happened I can
actually show it to you let me zoom in a
little bit more let's use the satellite
image okay here you have satellite
imagery and this attack
happened let me try and zoom in and see
if I can find the
place
okay so this is the embassy of the
Islamic Republic of Iran this is the
embassy of Canada and there's a building
in between which is the Iranian
consulate this building that is
sandwiched between the two embassies
Canada and Iran
that is the Iranian consulate that was
bombed uh apparently six missiles were
launched from F35 fighter planes Israel
fighter ples okay now the question is
what does Iran do about this and some
people will say that if it's a
diplomatic uh building why were there
General military personnel in
that why were there military personnel
in a diplomatic
building let me explain something
something to you my friends every Ember
Embassy has military personnel they're
called military attaches or defense
attaches and every Embassy also has
Intelligence Personnel spies who are
given some diplomatic
title this is common
practice you will have serving military
personnel on diplomatic
deputation in embassies and consulates
there is nothing wrong or illegal about
that but I'm not saying that Israel has
done something terribly bad even the
Iranians have attacked embassies and all
in the past so there's no right or wrong
in this it's it's just the way the world
works now what does Iran do about this
if Iran does nothing then Iran kind of
lose credibility loses credibility and
then its enemies will fear it less so
Iran will have to do something what does
Iran do well Iran can activate various
proxies Iran's proxies exist in Yemen
the Ansah faction the huis Iran's
proxies are all across Iraq Iraq is what
more than 50% Shia definitely more than
40% Shia probably more than 50% Shia and
Iran is entirely Shia so there are Iran
Iran has plenty of allies in Iraq Iran
has allies in Lebanon Southern Lebanon
which is the hasah Iran has allies in
Hamas and Iran has allies in Syria as
well Syria the regime of Mr al- Assad is
allied with Iran and with Russia Russia
so Iran has lots of proxies it can
activate if it activates proxies in Iraq
that's going to be a problem for the
American troops who are occupying Iraq
Iraq is under us occupation in case you
are not aware the Iraqis want the
Americans to leave but the Americans are
saying no we will not
leave then if there is an activation of
Iranian Proxes in Syria well you should
know that the West the eastern part of
Syria is under us occupation okay uh The
Americans have
troops in in the Eastern corner of Syria
it could be a problem was for those
troops if Iran if Iran activates its
proxies in Syria if Iran activates
hisbah and and turns Israel's northern
border into a hot border it's again a
problem for Israel and then then Iran
can also activate the huis to strike at
Israeli or American shipping vessels in
the Gulf of
Aden and India the Indian Navy is
currently patrolling this region but IND
the Indian Navy's operations are
typically aimed at uh controlling
Somalian
pirates not it is not aimed at the houis
and the houis have also not taken any
kind of hostile action against the
Indian Navy so there's a lot going on
here but if Iran wants to maintain
credibility it will have to perhaps
launch a direct strike at Israel which
could possibly mean some kind of missile
strike at various positions within
Israel there are plenty of strategic
targets from an Iranian perspective
within Israel so they could launch
missile strikes maybe cruise missiles
maybe ballistic missiles I'm just
imagining okay possible scenario
hypothetical scenario they could even
launch drone swarms at Israel from
within perhaps Syria from perhaps within
Iraq or somewhere else or even from
Lebanon who knows so plenty of possib is
exist the important thing is that if
Iran does
not respond if Iran does not
retaliate then it will lose
credibility so that is a
deal that's a deal
okay okay
now mugara says if World War II did not
happen would we would we be still R
ruled by the BR
probably not the Americans would have
found a way to to rule the world because
they were just the US is just too large
it's too vast it has too many resources
and they would have anyhow found a way
to Elbow the British out so see look
we're talking about alternate history
here lots of things could have happened
but most likely it just makes sense that
a nation that uh that occupies an
essentially an entire continent at least
half of a continent the better half they
they would find a way to rule the world
so I don't know I I guess the Americans
would have found a way to take
over
okay once again shama do you agree with
the Western idea of equality where woman
and a man should be treated equally I
believe that even if a woman slaps a man
and she's wrong A man should not slap
back look you can believe whatever you
want everybody can believe what whatever
they want I believe in people getting
equality of opportunity and equality of
Rights and also
perhaps equality of
Duties uh so today in today's world
physical strength doesn't matter that
much because we have technology where
you can be the weakest person physically
but you can La you can wield enormous
power look at us humans we are the
weakest physically of all the Apes our
chimpanzee cousins who are smaller than
us in stature they are way stronger than
us physically the gorilla another of our
relatives very close relatives is is
humongously powerful physically compared
to a human the utan the Gibbon all these
various Apes tailless monkeys they're
all physically stronger than us and yet
we are the dominant species because of
the intelligence So Physical strength no
longer matters so when it comes to
genders uh obviously the males in the
human species are more powerfully built
uh the females are not but today that
doesn't matter so I
believe that every
member of society should have the same
should have equality of
opportunities equality of opportunity
and and equal laws there should be no
discrimination based on gender or or
whatever but you cannot have equality of
outcome okay equality of opportunity and
then may the best win so it should be
equality of opportunity and Merit a
merit based system now whether a woman
slaps a man and she's wrong then a man
should not slap back well I'm not
getting into that kind of thing uh
nobody should slap anybody that's my
point okay uh but I believe that
everybody should get the same
opportunities and everybody should be
governed by the same laws irrespective
of their gender I think that's how it
should be and I think that's where India
is today isn't it uh maybe women are
more privileged perhaps than men in
India today according to the
laws
okay now
geopolitical duas say what if the split
part of East Africa slams Southern India
will it cause another mountain range
like the Himalayas okay let me put the
map on the
screen of the split part of East Africa
not sure which split part it is let's
say Madagascar okay Madagascar is this
gigantic Island over here let us say for
some reason because of some
tectonic activity
Madagascar slams into Southern India so
what do you mean by slamming we to First
Define slamming India broke away the the
Indian subcontinent broke away from
Africa more than 100 million years ago
and it started colliding with Eurasia
about 50 to 40 million years
ago and it is still colliding so in Geo
geological terms a collision takes
something between 10 to 50 million years
that's what we call slamming in
geology okay so a collision in in
geology in sense of geology takes
between 10 to 50 million years so for
this part of East Africa to slam into
Southern India we will have to wait for
about 10 to 50 million
years I'm sure I'll not be around by the
time but yeah if it happens it will
certainly cause another mountain range
to emerge similar to the Himalayas for
sure it will
okay hitan Sharma says when space travel
and human settlement on Mars happens
successfully how will land division
happen on the moon or Mars between
countries good question you're going to
have eventually if there is a successful
settlement of humans on the moon on Mars
very soon people are going to start
claiming territories so let's say the US
sends a
a bunch of humans to the Moon which will
happen soon and then they set up a lunar
base then the Indians do that India will
send by 202 2035 2040 thereabouts humans
on on on the moon India will also set up
a base on the moon the Chinese by the
time will do that the Russians want to
do it so let's say by 24 let's say by
2050 okay by 20150 there is an American
base on the moon there is an Indian base
on the moon a Chinese base and a Russian
base so initially there's going to be
significant geographical distance
between these bases and these will be
small bases maybe one base will have
five to 10 people at a given point in
time but by 2100 these bases will expand
become like towns or cities and then
people will start Nations will start
claiming
territories and the same thing will
happen in Mars okay this is our
Sovereign territory nobody comes here
that sort of thing and eventually once
these settlements become self-
sustaining
in the future and they don't have to
rely on Earth for supplies they will
probably declare independence from Earth
and they will set up their own Nations
that may also happen so it's an organic
process it's something that happens over
time organically spontaneously that's
what history tells us so initially
Australia was a colony of
England it is still technically under
the under the British crown but it's a
Nation today the United States started
as a colony of England and it declared
independence it fought a war of
independence against the British because
the British wanted to tax them
2% what is the income tax in the US
today more than 40% in some cases and
the people are happy with that but they
fought fought a war of independence for
2%
tax that's so the wolves have turned
into sheep essentially anyhow that's a
different story so that's how it happens
organically
spontaneously eventually that sort of
thing will happen
okay all
right
[Music]
um what else do we
have geopolitical says do you think
India and China will have a cold war 2.0
we are in a Cold War 2 the Cold War 2.0
is
between one part of the world and
another part of the world it's between
the Western Le world the Western World
which is led by the US and the Eastern
World which is an amalgam of of of China
and Russia Iran Syria all these nations
there is a cold war that's already
happening Cold War 2.0 it's not between
India and China it's between China
Russia and the West Iran is part of
China Russia and so is Syria and so are
some other nations like North Korea and
so on uh so that's the new Cold War the
Cold War
2.0 uh and when it comes to India and
China we are in a state of Cold War we
are not we're not the best of friends
we're not even bad friends we're not
friends at all it's pretty
hostile uh so yeah it's a cold war but
one hopes it doesn't become a hot War
because that would be bad for either
country
okay
uh W Shukla says what do you think of
India taking back aai chain as hard
power or using military is the only
option unlike P where a lot of Civil War
will lead it to break apart you know
what I am I am of the opinion that India
should right now for forget about taking
back territories we have
lost focus on building India's economic
power and hard power focus on that for
the next 10 20 years forget about all
these territories that have gone the
stronger you get the easier it becomes
to get these territories back when you
are so strong wrong that nobody can
challenge you those territories will
automatically fall back into your lab so
let us forget about taking this or that
territory back focus on the hard thing
which is to grow India's economy and as
you grow India's economy India's hard
power will also grow automatically
that's what India has to do without hard
power there is no taking back po or Ain
or
whatever so let's say you are up against
a sumo wrestler who is 300 kilos and you
weigh 75 kilos
and you're thinking about taking
something he has taken from you first
try and build some muscle will you it's
going to take some time to do that
you're going to have to do a lot of hard
lifting day after day at the
gym so focus on that then we'll talk
about taking things back and once that
guy is 300 kilos but you have become 400
kilos hard muscle not fat then that guy
will automatically give it back to you
Leo so that's what India has to do let's
forget about taking this or that back
when it comes to Pakistan that Nation
will break up automatically it's a
matter of time I call it a temporary
Nation with good with good there a good
there a good reason for calling it a
temporary Nation it's an artificial
nation which is temporary in nature
China is a different Beast so let's
first rise rise to to a comparable level
with China understand China is way
stronger than India Today understand
that China's economy is five times of
India and China's hard power is about
three and a half half times there of
India so let's build our power
first I'm really tired of this talk
about taking back p and oygen and all
that it will happen but it takes time
it's not going to happen next week or
next month forget about that focus on
the basics
first
okay
uh sag Sharma says what language do you
think will be the best to replace
English in bhat only one language can is
is in there's only one language that can
claim the status of India civilization
language throughout history and that is
sanskrit I hope that one day everybody
in India will be speaking Sanskrit as
the official national civilizational
language only one language can claim
that status only Sanskrit no other
language so that is the best language
and the only language that can be used
to replace India English as the official
civilizational language in
Barat
okay akiles says if you could travel
back in time with the time machine what
what message would you would you convey
to three different historical leaders
and why if I had access to a time
machine I would never go back in time
because you go back in time you
interfere with causality with the causal
structure of the
universe and even the air that you
breathe can cause
changes and it can end up messing up the
the future timeline of the world you
don't want to do that I would if I had a
time machine I would go to the
future I I go and try and see what the
future is like so if you go to the
Future from the past you're not messing
with the the causal structure of the
universe okay and then you can come back
and understand that okay this is what
may happen in what has happened in the
future so let's try and re-engineer the
today's world and and take actions that
will maybe not that will ensure that
that bad scenario doesn't happen and
maybe something else happens so if I had
a time machine I would go to the Future
maybe 20 years in the future then maybe
50 years in the future maybe then 100
years in the future and then maybe a
thousand years in the
future to understand what the future is
like
so that I can come back here and then
perhaps take some actions that can bring
about a different future maybe a better
future that's what I would do I would
not go back to the
past
okay okay Khan Rafa Ali says if China
were to attack both p and Jammu and
Kashmir simultaneously is there a
hypothetical possibility for a military
Alliance to occur between India and
Pakistan back by us
blessings well well well that's it's a
very interesting scenario that we bring
about ali
so if China were to attack both Po and
Jammu and Kashmir
simultaneously why would China do that
China already has access to
PO uh they are building that so-called
CPC infrastructure through through po
China Pakistan economic Corridor which
is kind of defunct but they were
building something there there was a
presence of Chinese troops of a certain
amount a certain level in po so they
Chinese already have access to
Pok uh but let's say they attack Po in
Jammu and Kashmir
simultaneously uh I don't think there is
a possibility of of any kind of alliance
between India and Pakistan and US
blessings
um it's always best not to be blessed by
the US you know it's always best um so
what I can say is that this scenario is
first of all uh not feasible from the
perspective of the logic of strategy
because China and Pakistan they kind of
align strategically Visa India Pakistan
today is very much firmly back in the
US saddle let's let's say but uh there
is some Synergy between India between
Pakistan and China when it comes to the
relationship with India so I don't see
pakist the Chinese ever attacking po
they may attack Jammu and Kashmir that
may happen but po simply can't
happen um so and even if it happens I
don't see India and Pakistan fighting
together the DNA of the two militaries
is so different they can't fight
together especially the Pakistan
military they they just condition to see
India as the enemy no matter what
happens so it is unlikely this scenario
is unlikely and secondly the India and
Pakistan coming together with with us
blessings that is also extremely
unlikely I I don't see that happening in
in this hypothetical
scenario okay Mah Manesh Kash says the
Empire of chakrawarti samrat
vikramaditya permar of aanka real or
just a popular as myth was his Empire
bigger and stronger than the Moran
Empire and versus Julius Caesar uh
vicrad permar there were so many viadas
that I'm not sure which one this one is
this is
but I don't think any Empire of vikia
was greater than that of the morian
Empire so the morian Empire it
essentially had all of India unified
politically and when I'm talking about
India I'm talking about gandar as well
so president of Pakistan president of
Afghanistan up to the border of
Tajikistan and much of the rest of
India uh very few empires have have
eclipsed that in terms of area under
control probably keska had a greater
Empire greater extent of Empire because
his Empire touched the Aral Sea and the
Caspian Sea as well as it included Tibet
and shinjang and obviously the Chola
Empire included the included the whole
of Southeast
Asia uh yeah so that sort of
thing so I think the Moran Empire was
probably greater and when it comes to
Julius Caesar uh let's go to the map so
Caesar Kaiser Julius Kaiser he was from
Italy he conquered the whole of France
today he conquered let's let's call it
Southern Germany what is today
Switzerland he conducted a tremendous
genocide of the Celtic people in France
in in Switzerland he uh conquered Iberia
which is present day Spain much of it he
conquered parts of the British Islands
then he also conquered Greece uh and he
also conquered Egypt so that's quite a
reasonably large empire the cholas
conquered all of Southeast Asia up to
the
Philippines so that is kind of similar
if not larger than the than the Roman
Empire when it comes to the morans they
conquered the whole of the subcontinent
more or less when it comes to the guptas
under kumara Gupta I think they
conquered balik which is all the way to
usbekistan Tajikistan turkistan and they
also had regions up to Shri Lanka so all
these Empires had different sizes and
shapes and characteristics
uh so yeah that's about it but I'm not
sure about vicrad parar of aanika how
large or small his Empire was I'm not
very can't remember exactly when this
happened and how large it was so not
sure if I can answer the question but I
hope I have given
reasonably varied
context okay let's see what else we
have geopolitical says what's the
relation between the the Celtic goddess
danu and the rvic danu same
goddess both are river
goddesses there's a balines
goddess in Bali today they still pray to
a goddess called danu in Bali in
Indonesia and that danu is also a river
goddess okay so in the
Riga there was this lady called danu
she's she's a goddess and she was was
the mother of a large number of sons and
they were called the
danavas and the danavas were kind of
nasty evil people they were opposed to
the to the gods let's say so it is kind
of asuras versus suras that's of dasas
versus asuras kind of thing and there
was a fight between the dasas and the
danavas and the danavas were defeated
and they were expelled out of araar out
of
India and then they are expelled and
their story ends but it so that is what
we know from the Riga that they they
were defeated now if you look at so so
danu was this River goddess okay she was
a river goddess now if you go to uh so
for the longest time what is today
called Central Asia was once called
skiya the Shaka people used to live
there the shakas were Indian origin
people the westerners will call Western
historians will call them Iranian people
but they were Indian origin people and
they eventually they they ruled Central
Asia for several thousand years and
about 2,000 years before today they
re-entered India as Invaders and
conquerors and they reassimilated with
the Indian population that's a skan
invasion of India and their kings were
eventually called the mahak
chatas the great satrs the northern
satraps and the Western SATs the Western
satraps were based in Gujarat and they
controlled the great ports the great
ports that were the gatway of India for
the Western World for trade with Rome
and Egypt and all that and there were
also the Lords and protectors of the
great uh Jing at snat these indos skan
Kings so for the longest time Central
Asia was called skia and the skan word
for water was
danu okay the skan word for water was
danu now there are there's a bunch of
rivers in Europe we know there is a
massive war going on in Ukraine the
capital of of Ukraine is Kiev yes Kiev
so this River the city KV is setting
arride a river and that river is the
giper
ner and then there is a a d River in the
East let us find the D River okay over
here
mova here you have a d so you have a d
and a
giper so the dier is the danu
apara and the N is the danu asara or
something like that so the upper danu
and the lower danu then you have the
danub which is another great river in
Europe which is also named after danu
then you have the
ranu the ranu is now called Theon the
city of Geneva the river that goes
through it is called Theon r h o n e
historically historically it was called
the ranu so there's a whole bunch of
rivers in Europe
the ner the
ne the
duina
dunay the danub the ranu and so on and
so forth a whole bunch of rivers across
you know Europe that is named after danu
which kind of traces the westward
migration of the danava people and they
end up in
Ireland and the ancient people of
Ireland the mythological ancestors of
the Irish people were called the
the danan the peoples of the goddess
danu and that goddess danu the Irish
goddess danu was also a river goddess
and there you have it that's the
religion it's the same goddess no matter
what these historians say it is the same
goddess the same goddess is still woried
in Indonesia again called danu all right
that is about
that okay prati V says why is the
international tourist inflow in India
very low when we are the longest
continuously existing civilization with
so many places to explore and history
culture food
Etc I think Bangkok in one year gets
more tourists than the whole of
India Bangkok our neighboring country
Thailand right next door you can fly
from Kolkata to Bangkok in less than two
hours I'm sure and so on so why is that
so look we may we may have the greatest
culture the oldest history and so on but
if we don't make a tourists welcome feel
welcome they won't come how do you make
tourists feel feel welcome they should
have a smooth process of entering the
country no long lines for stamping Visa
or whatever okay a Visa process has to
be there but when you enter India for
immigration let's say through a cruise
ship the process should be smooth it
should take 5 minutes not two hours in
the heat standing under the sun yeah
then once you are inside India once you
have crossed the immigration threshold
you should have good infrastructure
let's say you want to visit agenta caves
or aora caves very interesting
historical place you want to go there
how do you get there if I was a tourist
I would want to go by plane I want to
take a plane Journey get off there get
on a taxi and be there in 5 minutes 10
hours half an hour 10 minutes half an
hour I don't want to take a 5 hour road
journey and once I reach there there
there isn't good infrastructure I don't
have a good hotel there no air
conditioning no good restaurants no good
toilet facilities and so
on I don't want to have to deal with
corrupt officials I don't want to have
to deal with bad roads bad
traffic and so on so there is a lack of
quality infrastructure in India things
are
improving but we are not there right now
do you
understand so a to if you are a tourist
you want a smooth experience you want a
pleasant experience you get that in
Thailand in Bangkok you get there in
Turkey you get that in
Greece even CH the Chinese are rolling
out the red carpet you get that in Japan
in India it's still not there India is a
potential tourism
superpower but for that we will have to
invest in quality infrastructure and in
making tourists feel really welcome
it's not there it's not there right
now that's the problem tourism can
contribute a tremendous amount to
India's
GDP but that money will not go into the
pockets of politicians it'll go straight
into the public coffers it will help the
local
shops local restaurants local hotels it
won't help the local polititions so
that's a problem you know so that is the
reason tourists the don't typically have
a great experience in India in some
parts of India the experience is great
but in most Parts it's not that great
especially if you're interested in
visiting historical sites and all uh the
the maintenance of the historical sites
is terrible unless it is a mul or
monument like Taj Mahal right and and
there may be restrictions in some places
about partying or night life or
whatever in some states of India you
can't drink alcohol well tourists want
to enjoy everything they enjoy in other
places and so on so there are so many
issues right now which are kind of
frustrating India should do much so much
more it will take time one has to be
patient patient but yeah that's the
reason why India is still not that great
when it comes
to leveraging its tourism
potential
okay okay what do we
have what else do we
have Shadow
says can we make it so that we only give
Visa free to those who have Visa free
for us so there are a number of
countries that offer us either visa on
arrival or just Visa free
entry for
example you want to go to Iran let's say
for whatever reason you don't have to
apply for a Visa you go there and they
once you go there with your passport
they will see your passport this time of
Visa there and you just enter the
country you don't have to go through a
visa application process uh when it
comes to Thailand same thing you go to
whatever place in Thailand and you will
get a visa on Entry stamp once you reach
the airport or whatever Port of Entry it
is if you want to go to the US if you
want to go to the European Union Nations
there a long tedious Visa procedure
which is actually quite
humiliating so the question is should we
have
reciprocity the Nations that give us
Visa free entry we give them Visa free
entry in some cases they will have
online e visas which is a very
straightforward process for those
Nations we give them also the same sort
of facility online e Visa electronic
visa and for those Nations that go make
us go through this TDS procedure we also
make them go through a teds procedure
how about that um I think we have
something like that we don't offer Every
Nation a Visa free access or or visa on
arrival access American cens who are
used to getting Visa free access almost
everywhere they complain that in India
we have to go through the Visa procedure
well what do you expect it's much easier
than what you make Indian citizens go
through when they want to visit the us
so I think there has to be some amount
of
reciprocity but in case we want certain
Nations to invest in India and we want
to attract their business we should
maybe give them preferential treatment
even though they may not give us the
same thing so it is all about putting
our interests first
let's say x Nation requires Indians to
go through the Visa procedure and apply
for a Visa and go to the Embassy and
spend some time and waste some time to
get a Visa but that nation has a lot of
money and we want to attract that money
into India we want them to invest in
India in that case despite them doing
this to us we may perhaps want to
consider giving them Visa free or visa
on arrival facilities so that we
can attract their investment and get and
they can it make it easy we can make it
easy for them to invest in India so it's
all about seeing who can offer us what
and uh that's how it
goes so in these matters we have to be
unemotional just look at it rationally
logically
okay let's see what else we
have uh vovi says why have Vic gods and
goddesses lost their relevance now we
now worship Shiva Vishnu and other gods
and invoke those Vic Gods at times of
rituals but not actively pray to them my
thoughts for for the first of all Lord
Shiva is a Vic God the name has changed
we we call him Lord we call him shiv
today or Mahadev or
Mahesh but we also call him rudra we
these days nobody uses the term rudra
for him in the Riga he is called rudra
today we call him Shiva so it's the same
God it's a Vic
God Shiva is the oldest of the
Gods um he's the only truly Supernatural
God in in Hinduism you know uh there is
the you must have I I hope you know
about the nasad suta in the r the
creation hymn In which is you know what
it says that in the beginning there was
nothing but darkness and darkness
enveloped in darkness and nothing was
created and then everything appeared out
of that darkness and the universe was
created or something along those lines
and even the gods the vidc gods are part
of the universe they were created with
the universe so who created
them and the
Creator does he know who created them
all or does he does he himself not
know so it's a very agnostic kind of
creation hymn that we have in Hinduism
it says that even these Vic
Gods came with the universe it's a
package deal once the universe was
created these Gods came with the
universe so even they were born with the
birth of the universe so what came
before that who created the universe who
created all of this and does he know or
does he also not know what's the origin
of creation so that's a s of thing
and the only truly Supernatural God is
Shiva because he is supposed to be the
Timeless God the God that was that
existed before the universe and will
exist after this universe dies because
the universe is a life cycle it's kind
of Multiverse cosmology that we have a
cyclical Universe kind of thing uh and
multiple universes and all and Shiva is
the is the god who is beyond death and
time
rudra um so first of all rudra is
probably the oldest and most primordial
God the there are some other gods that
are kind of gone out of relevance no one
remembers them we talk about Indra and
all these Gods does anybody remember
Theos
pitu nobody remembers dios petu the
father of Indra the father of all the
gods but once again dipu himself was a
part of the universe so he came with the
package DE after the creation of of the
Universe um but so Indian history is so
so
old that even gods have kind of fallen
into the background so like you
rightfully say nobody prays to Indra
today there was a time when Indra was
the well the God of War the god of
Victory the first God you would pray to
before you went into battle and so on uh
then he becomes the god of rain and
today he becomes some kind of well he
has become a caric he is now looked upon
as kind of a caricature of what he used
to be so Gods also kind of fall out of
favor that's how old Indian history is
thousands and thousands of years so New
Gods take precedence old gods kind of
Fade Into the background but they are
still kind of around there and today in
our our rituals and Vic rituals and all
we still invoke the old gods and that's
how it is so sometimes the new gods have
the characteristics of the old gods and
so on so it's it's it's quite complex
and this all is a very good indicator of
how old Indian history is Evol
cultural Evolution religious Evolution
but the oldest God is Shiva and he is
still very much relevant he used to be
called rudra rudra om bhag om Nam bhag
rudraa that's how the rudri part goes
right the rudri part it's part of the
yaja I don't remember which Veda but it
starts with om Nam bhag rudraa which is
Shiva but they used to call him rudra
back in the day a few thousand years ago
okay M Ry says how did Afghanistan
become an Islamic country what was it
like there before becoming Islamic
Afghanistan is gandhar the northern
Northwestern part of historical India
the land the The Province from which uh
gandhari the queen gandhari originated
and her brother
shakuni so it was very much Indian uh
for the longest part in longest period
in history but then things changed you
had the turkic invasions and the first
part of India to fall to the turkic
invasions was Was northwestern India
which is Afghanistan so before
Afghanistan was Islamic there was a
there was this Buddhist period and
before the Buddhist period there was
obviously the Vic
period uh so that's how it was all of
Central Asia was
Hindu when the skians ruled Central Asia
at that time and before the skians it
was all a Hindu land you have very
ancient ruins of Hindu temples which
then have been converted into something
else into a later foreign
religion
so Afghanistan the the process of
Afghanistan becoming Islamic begins
about a thousand years before today the
Gories The Gories were a Buddhist
Dynasty The Gories were a Buddhist
Dynasty and then you know what happened
so to put very
simply
Afghanistan was the original
Kashmir what happened to Kashmir in the
past 300 years 400 years is what first
happened to Afghanistan exactly the same
thing today if you go to Afghanistan
there's this ethnic cocktail a mix of
ethnicities the predominant ethnicity is
the pashun and then you have the eks and
the hazaras and the tajiks and the
various other ethnicities
the
tajiks you could say are the natives to
some extent more in Tajikistan the
pashun are the true native of
Afghanistan the usbek and the and the
and the whatever else those are turkic
Invaders who then were settled in
Afghanistan uh so they're not really
Afghans actually but today obviously
they've been living in Afghanistan for
several hundred years so yeah and
they've all kind of intermingled
intermixed today so yeah they're all
Afghans today but the true native of
Afghanistan are the
pashun and so on long process standard
process of how it
happens uh but yeah you could you could
say that Afghanistan is the first
Kashmir and then the same thing happened
to
Kashmir
okay okay what
else okay Babar C duber says why is
there a global rise of the right wing
is it because of the hypocrisy of the
left or is there more to it okay let me
think about it where is there a global
rise of the right wing in India there's
no right-wing if you think the BJP is
right-wing that's not quite true the BJP
is is kind of a Centrist
party it's not a right-wing
party if it was a right-wing party India
would have been declared a Hindu Nation
by today India the BJP is more of a
Centrist party okay it's not leftwing by
any means it not it's not rightwing also
it's kind of you know doing a balancing
act it is still following the Indian
constitution and secularism and all that
and much more so there is no okay people
in India identify the BJP as a
right-wing party but they're not quite
correct in that lots of people in India
call themselves right-wingers the vote
for the BJP which is good but
uh and that is kind of a reaction to
centuries of
Oppression and also a reaction to all
the uh policies
of the Indian government since 1947 all
the way to 2014 and then there was a big
reaction to that so it's a natural
reaction it's going to happen now is
there a global rise of the right wing
let's see is there a rise of the right
wing in the UK not quite is there a rise
of the rightwing in let's say France
well m m is not a right- Winger he's
kind of a lefty is there a of the
rightwing in
Germany no no no no no the rise of the
right wi in Germany means marching boots
again
okay so that is not going to
happen uh is there a rise of the right
wing in the U us well you've got the
lefties in power today M Biden Mr Biden
is a lefty is a Democrat the Republicans
are not in power let's see if they
manage to return to power in this year's
election we don't know we'll see about
that so I'm not sure there is a global
rise of the right wi there is certainly
a reaction to all the Lefty policies
that are being followed across the
European Union and the Western World
which is becoming more and more left
dominated there's going to be some
reaction but they aren't really
succeeding in coming to power as such
there a reaction that's visible but
who's dominating who's in power who's
running the government mostly it's the
left
wing
yeah
okay all right
um Nala says what's the history of the
British Indian Ocean territory how did
it end up in the end up in the hands of
the British and the Americans was it
owned by the cholas look I have a whole
video that came out just about a week or
so ago about this matter but let me just
give you
brief
recap this British Indian Ocean
territory okay it's south of India in
the uh Indian Ocean region okay one
thing I have to clarify I get a lot of
comments these days so I have this video
in which I am in a hotel room and I show
The View outside of the hotel room
there's the sea there I say it's the
Indian Ocean and most people will
understand that I was in Mumbai at the
time so people were correcting me in the
comments no it's not the Indian Ocean
it's the Arabian
Sea it really annoyed me and I don't
blame those people for those comments I
blame their geography teachers the AR
the so-called Arabian Sea is part of the
Indian Ocean
the Gulf of Adan is part of the Indian
Ocean okay the mozambik channel between
Madagascar and and Africa is part of the
Indian Ocean the lakshadweep Sea is part
of the Indian Ocean the Bay of Bal is
part of the Indian Ocean the Andaman Sea
is part of the Indian Ocean what sort of
geography are these people teaching you
if you think that the Arabian Sea is not
part of the Indian Ocean it is so
annoying to see the low standards of
India's geography teachers who have
brainwashed an entire entire generations
of kids into thinking that the Arabian
Sea is not part of the Indian
Ocean it's it's just it's it's beyond
belief that this is what is being taught
anyhow coming back to your
question okay this so we have the Le
Islands here
okay Southwest of India in the Indian
Ocean south of the lead you have the Mal
Dives and south of the mald you have the
British Indian Ocean territory now this
British Indian Ocean territory used to
be administered from
macius and in 1965 before the British
gave Independence of the Macias they
detached the British Indian Ocean
territory from the macius in
contravention of of United Nations
agreements and then they handed over
this to the US okay so I'm not sure if
the cholas ruled it probably not but it
it was known to ancient Indians the
Maldives and the LX Islands were settled
by ancient Indians about 3,000 or so
years ago and in the past 700 800 years
the malis became islamized before that
it was Hinduism and Buddhism there and
sometimes people would get stranded on
these islands in the chos
archipelago and then they would have to
be rescued in a few months so Indians
knew about this territory but we did not
occupy this
territory and so the British handed over
this this base Diego Garcia to the
Americans in
1973 so the Americans supported the
pakistanis in the 1971 War when the
pakistanis were conducting a genocide of
mostly Hindus in East Pakistan and India
had to respond to Pakistani first
strikes Air Force strikes on Indian
Territory and that's how the war begins
1971 and the British and the Americans
sent two aircraft sorry aircraft carrier
task forces in the Bay of Bengal to
bully India to intimidate India and to
force India into not attacking Pakistan
and they would have succeeded but the
Russians sent a fleet of nuclear
submarines to face off against the
British and and the Americans and they
the British and the Americans had to
back off so because of this Russian
action India was able to go ahead with
the war and liberate Bangladesh and take
Dhaka and give Bangladesh freedom from
Pakistan so that made it very clear in
1971 To America that they needed a
permanent base in this region from which
they could project power so two years
later they acquired this territory Diego
Garcia and it technically should belong
to the mald to the to to maius uh the UN
has made it amply clear that Britain
does not have any sovereignty over this
but the British refused to give it away
to give it back to the rightful owner
which is morous so on the one hand they
talk about Russia occupying parts of
Ukraine and they want India to support
Ukraine in this on the other hand the
British and the Americans are occupying
territory that belongs to morus the UN
and the international court of justice
Etc have made it very clear that the UK
has no sovereignty over these over these
islands and they have to return it
immediately but they're not doing it
absolute double standards and hypocrisy
so that is the deal with the so-called
British Indian Ocean territory
right
okay okay let's let's let's try
and see something
different some of
questions let us see let us
see
um okay let's see this question by Bobby
good to see Bobby after a long time
hope you're doing well so magically
India dropped from fifth in top World
Cuisines to 11th in one year span
according to tast Atlas swap with China
China
did did Indian Cuisine change
drastically who paid who look these
indexes indices rankings and all they
are very
subjective uh it's all based on opinions
of of a small number of people who we
don't and we don't know who they are
so-called experts but who are these
experts what what are the methodology by
which you did the rankings how do you
determine something as subjective as as
culinary taste and quality not sure so
yeah magically I I was not even aw aware
of this this particular taste Atlas
ranking but Okay so we've dropped from
fifth to 11th in one year and we have
sought with China so yeah maybe somebody
was paid maybe there was some financial
transaction that happened I don't know
these days there is this uh concerted
effort to kind of push India down
denigrate India um as India rises in
terms of hard power and
geopolitical relevance they're trying to
push India down in other ways uh to kind
of affect the moral of the people of
India and to kind of you know create a
certain impression of India the people
should not under realize in the Western
World especially that India is rising so
put India down in other
ways claim that India is number 385 in
the world happiness rankings let's say
or 782 whatever it is and say that India
is no longer a democracy India is an
authoritarian Nation so put India 111th
in the world democracy index or whatever
and so on so these are just you know
mind games that they are playing in
sports you have something called
sledging especially in team sports so if
you play cricket and you're typically
doing the batting then the opposition
team the bowlers fielders they're going
to try and intimidate you and and and
disparage you and mock you abuse you the
Australians used to be really good at
this that's the same kind of thing the
West is doing to India today we need to
just ignore it enjoy the cuisine you
enjoy you like Indian food enjoy it
forget about other people's opinions how
do do people's opinions matter I
personally like all kinds of Cuisines
but obviously Indian Cuisine is the best
so as far as I'm concerned India is
number one number
one in the world world rankings of in in
Cuisine
okay
H Tamil or Sanskrit which is
older and did they both evolve with each
other I'm not getting into this I have
taken this question so many times
there's always this war going
on I don't know doesn't matter both are
Indian languages India is the oldest
civilization both are the oldest both
are number one there we have it
okay uh do voice call question answer
for your Discord server members the
request okay I'll I'll look into that
all right
sure if China attacks India is there a
chance India might win the war it
depends on the context it depends on the
scale of the war see if India and China
actually go to war hypothetically it
cannot be more than a limited War
because if it goes beyond a limited
War red lines are crossed
and if red lines are crossed both
Nations stand to lose a
lot China stands to lose more they stand
to lose everything they have worked for
in the last 40
years neither Nation can afford a war
going Beyond a limited war and when you
have a war that starts even if it's
limited War you never know what is going
to
happen in the fog of War Anything Can
Happen the best thing is there should be
no war beyond the threats and abuse and
saber rattling and all and the fist
fights and the stick fights nothing
beyond
that but if China does attack
India well if it's a limited War India
can defeat China in that and China may
end up losing some territory because the
war in the Himalayas cannot involve
tanks it will involve artillery but it
it will involve a lot of hand toand
Fighting manto Man
fighting and today the Indian army is
not show shorten arms on ammunation like
in the nouvian days in
1962 and today we have the
infrastructure the roads and all that
and the Chinese positions are very badly
exposed in Tibet there's no vegetation
in
Tibet it's all exposed so they're
building tunnels and all that but yeah
we can deal with that too so I don't
think a Chinese stand to win a local War
a localized limited War they may end up
being on the on the losing side and if
that happens
you know the Chinese Communist party is
a different kind of Beast they don't
tolerate failure and if there is a
failure the person at the top is held
accountable and it's
never it never ends well in that in that
scenario the Chinese won't attack
India if they attack India they may end
up losing if they end up being on on the
verge of losing they may be tempted to
expand the war Beyond a local War the
moment you the war Beyond a local war
and you hit certain Targets in India all
bets are
off so you don't want to be in that
position because we're talking about the
the thing that we shall not talk about
which is the nuclear option we don't
ever want that to come into play so I
think the Chinese aren't mad they they
have some sanity they're not crazy
people I don't think it's going to
happen if there's a war in the future it
will not be started by India that is a
guarantee India won't start it so it's
up to the Chinese do you guys want a war
we don't want a war we won't start one
if a war happens you're going to start
it so have some sense and don't start a
war that's
it
okay Karan naat says can mathematics
students work in the field of cosmology
of course you can work in the field of
cosmology all you need to do physics is
mathematics
if you are good at math you can do any
physics learning the basic principles of
physics is so easy if you know math it's
it's a piece of cake you already have
the tools needed it may take you just a
couple of weeks to understand the basic
concepts of physics because you already
have the tools the math you don't the
main problem that physics students face
is to have to learn the maths needed to
solve physics problems but a math
student already has the knowledge
it's actually
easy cosmology is I mean yeah it's easy
no big deal the only real problem that
students who want to learn physics face
is that you have to first learn the math
and pretty complex mathod that well
tensor calculus is kind of
complex uh linear algebra matrices
differential equations set theory and so
on and so forth so math students already
have many of these tools it's it's
actually easy for them
yeah okay okay we have crossed two hours
so we are coming to the end of today's
session let's
[Music]
see let's see if I can take some a
couple more interesting
questions
okay man says have you read the novels
by SL bppa I have not yet read those
novels I've heard they really good what
is it
called aaran the wheel and maybe a
couple else a couple other books I
haven't read yet I've heard they really
good
okay
uh okay where else are we what else are
we
doing okay sidar Singh rajit says we
haven't as we haven't explored most of
the earth is there a possibility of
another human species other than Homo
sapiens without our knowledge we have
explored the entire surface of the Earth
we have satellite mapping we have
satellite technology there's no part of
the surface of the Earth that has not
been explored that's for sure okay maybe
there could be the yeti living in some
parts of the Himalayas because the
Himalayas are so inaccessible okay
perhaps maybe there's a small
possibility that the yeti migy migy
exists in sikim and Tibet and and vak or
whatever but that possibility is small
apart from the Himalayas and apart from
some places we've kind of seen
everything and even when it comes to the
Himalayas we can still see what's
happening through satellite images even
though it's humans may not have reached
every part of the Himalayas because it's
so inaccessible inhospitable and so on
so it is very very very unlikely that
there's another human species somewhere
right now in the past when it comes to
uh parts of
Indonesia uh suaves or whatever there
was this Hobbit species that kind of
died out apparently about 10,000 years
ago or something U but overall I I
believe that on balance the likelihood
of a different another human species
existing today is extremely low
extremely
low
okay uh in France has wanted to say
thank you and Dand pronoun to you for
being a teacher we could never get in
our schools May sham bless you with
happiness and prosperity thank you so
much I really appreciate that thank you
so
much
okay so many questions let's
see is it true that India lost 2
kilometers square kilometers planned to
China and ladak as per Wikipedia what is
aun
map look
here this is the Indian version of
Google Maps you you use the American
version or any non-indian version of
Google Maps you'll see a different
variety of map so this entire region
here you see pangong Lake this here is
pangong
Lake north of pangong Lake north of Goa
hot springs and all this entire region
is occupied by China right now I'm sure
it's significant territory then you have
parts of utar utarak Etc small parts
that are occupied by China
and so on the border is not defined in
1962 and even before that and sometimes
even after that the Chinese have taken
grabbed significant portions of Indian
Territory and they have kept on and
they've kept up with those salami
slicing ter tactics the same tactics
they use in the South China Sea with the
Philippines with Vietnam with other
countries the same thing they are doing
they've been doing with India whatever
territory we have lost to China in ladak
and other parts of India happened during
the time of nehu and before
2014 of course we have lost it I have
been there I have videos on this channel
reporting from chushul reporting from
other places you can see Chinese
occupied ladak from there you can see
the Chinese Highway the highway they
have built you can see Chinese vehicles
there and you can feel the Chinese
binoculars at on your face you can feel
it you can see the bunkers on the
Hills we have lost territory it's not
happened since 2015 14 it's all happened
before 2014 after 2014 the government of
India has ramped up construction
infrastructure building efforts and
that's why there have been so many
clashes with the Chinese because they
are now ruffled they are worried it's no
longer the previous governments who will
let the Chinese do whatever they want so
India has lost
territory 62 is the major loss after 62
also they've been slicing away Indian
Territory now they can't and that's the
problem from their perspective itive so
yes we have lost territory but those
idiots who say because of Modi what
nonsense what delusional idiotic world
are they living in it really annoys me
really annoys me that people won't think
with the their brains that the gods have
given them they will simply listen to
the opinions of influencers without
actually opening a book or opening a map
or reading up a little bit because
reading takes takes effort right
thinking is hard work I don't want to
think I'll simply swallow other people's
opinions
so
frustrating so
frustrating
okay ual says yet it doesn't exist well
some people say God doesn't exist
because they've never seen the seen
God the absence of evidence is not
evidence of
absence I also haven't seen a Yeti I
haven't
seen I haven't seen a blue whale so from
my perspective I can claim the blue
whale doesn't exist look like I said the
probability of an unknown species of
humanoid existing in sikim in ladak in
Tibet is very low but it is not zero you
cannot claim to know everything that
happens in the
world you can't have that
certainty so people who say that God
doesn't
exist have you seen the entire
universe 95% of the is
dark we don't know what's happening in
95% of the universe so how can you claim
you understand the entire universe and
you know for sure that God or whatever
else doesn't exist how can you make the
claim to make that claim you you
actually need to be God yourself it's so
illogical that people come up with these
absolute
claims it actually well it's kind of an
indicator of the intelligence of a
person
okay somi Jen says please wish me luck I
have G main on 8th of April all the best
sir do well do really well I hope that
you have studied sufficiently now trust
your your your your studies trust the
hard work and I hope that you get the
best possible result all the
best okay okay so now where are we
let me take one more
question it's 2 hours 10
minutes and let us see
um Babar kadab says how do you when do
you see the Russia versus Ukraine War
ending is there any possibility of NATO
sending its troops in the future the
NATO Coalition seems to be considering
sending troops into Ukraine maybe
there's a chance they may send them to
to Odessa or some somewhere in the
southern part of Ukraine that would be a
tremendously dangerous red line to
cross because then you will have direct
confrontation between Russia and NATO
instead of the proxy war that's
happening right now that would be that
would be bad
escalation okay uh when do I see this
War ending not anytime
soon uh eventually it will end with the
partition of Ukraine it will it will end
on the terms of Russia most likely
Russia is no pushover it's the second
most powerful Nation on the planet where
more powerful than China unlike what
people think so it's going to end on
Russia's terms whenever Russia wants to
end it not anytime soon and if NATO
sends troops it's going to take us
closer to nuclear war actually I hope it
doesn't happen Mong Mr M has been
talking about sending French troops and
all are you people
serious
seriously what's he going to gain from
this anyhow so yeah not anytime soon is
what it looks like I could of course be
wrong but we'll
see geopolitical du says connection
between konar and karak I don't see any
connection I'm not aware of any
connection the names sound kind of
similar karak in Egypt Kar in in in
India in bhat in in Kalinga but I don't
know if there is any actual connection
sometimes there are in French in the
French language they call certain words
fosi false friends for example in French
the word for clothing is ABI h a b
the same word h a b t means Habit in
English but totally different words in
no connection with the same spelling so
these are false friends of fi like the
say in French sometimes you have such
such words such names like konar and
Karnak which may not actually have any
real connection so as far as I know I
have not seen any connection between the
two all right that brings us to the end
of today's session once again 2 hours 12
minutes plus thank you so much for all
the questions for all the wonderful
questions apologies once again to all
those of you whose questions I could not
take there are thousands of questions
and I only have two hours little bit
more than two hours but uh I'll keep on
doing this and eventually hopefully
everybody gets
to have me answer answer the question so
thank you once again for being on this
live stream with me thank you for
watching thank you for your viewership
thank you for your support keep raising
your standards all the best and I will
see you in a week or two in the next
live stream thank you good day goodbye
and good night wherever you are and see
you soon